In the last course, we have a basic understanding of CLO fabric.
In this course, we will learn CLO fabric in more depth.
First, let's get to know the 3D stickers and PBR stickers under the fabric texture attribute.
In 3D software, the physical visual effect of the object is usually expressed by using different PBR stickers.
Each sticker represents a visual texture attribute.
In CLO, you can use these six stickers.
Structure picture,發現 picture, illusion picture, transparent picture, surface roughness and metal picture.
When these stickers are used together, the texture will be more complete and realistic.
The first one is the structure picture.
Through the structure picture, the color or print of the fabric is displayed in 3D.
It is the most important sticker to express the texture visual effect.
The發現 picture is the second important sticker that is similar to the structure picture.
Through the發現 picture, the fine details of the fabric are displayed.
Such as the structure of the edge, the wrinkles, etc.
The發現 picture only increases the visual effect of the rough details.
From the side, the surface is still smooth and smooth.
The illusion picture can show the real roughness of the surface of the fabric.
The picture belongs to the gray picture.
The closer to the black part, the closer to the bottom of the material.
The closer to the white part, the closer to the material.
The picture is also the surface of the material.
In some cases, the illusion picture will add a high-definition blur.
To make the edges of the smooth figure.
The transparent picture defines the transparent and translucent degree of the surface of the fabric in some areas.
In CLO, there are two different sticker modes that express the transparency of the material, RGB and Alpha.
The RGB mode uses a gray picture with no transparency.
The closer the JPEG or JPEG to the white area, the less transparent it is, and the closer it is to the black area, the more transparent it is.
The depth of the grayness determines the degree of transparency.
In the alpha mode, use pictures in the form of .png, .tif, or .psd.
The alpha value of the transparent channel reflects the transparency effect.
The surface rough map controls the light information on the surface of the fabric, and thus expresses the roughness of the surface of the fabric.
The sticker is a gray map.
The closer to black, the more reflected light.
The closer to white, the less reflected light.
The metal map defines the area of the surface of the fabric with metal characteristics.
The sticker is a black and white image.
The black area represents non-metal materials.
The white area represents metal materials.
In CLO, the user can set the surface roughness plus the metalness,
and then combine the metal map to express the metal effect of the surface of the fabric.
How to get a seamless PBR sticker?
Method 1. Use an ordinary scanner, such as Canon, Epson, etc.
Scan the texture and process the seam to get a seamless texture.
Combine the PS software to generate other PBR stickers.
Method 2. Use a professional scanner.
Use a professional scanner, such as WeZoo, Revolbet, etc.
With professional pattern processing software,
you can scan, process and automatically generate various PBR stickers more efficiently.
Next, I will take you to the comprehensive practice of digital fabrics in CLO.
Open the library, select CLO Training, search for materials,
find materials, and learn more about CLO fabric documents.
Double-click to open.
You can see that this is a solid file that uses a default fabric.
Close the library window.
Next, we will add the corresponding fields to the completed PBR stickers.
In the object window, select the material 1.
In the attribute editor that is displayed below,
there are the corresponding add-on positions of the texture,
發現 picture, and change-in picture, etc.
There are four small square icons on the right side of each sticker column.
Add the corresponding stickers through it.
In the object window, click on the four small square icons.
Select the object.
Double-click to open at the bottom right.
At this time, a message will pop up.
Click .
You can add all PBR stickers at once.
Press .
Add the object again.
Click .
Only add the selected object.
If you want to add all the stickers at once,
click .
Note that each PBR sticker needs to be named according to the rules of the material name.
And all PBR pictures are placed in a folder.
Each PBR sticker has a corresponding add-on name,
as shown on the screen.
In the case of a texture,
Claw can automatically create a發現 picture.
There is an auto-create button on the right.
Click .
It can automatically create a發現 picture.
In the case of adding a texture,
the rest of the five PBR stickers,
such as the發現 picture,
the summoning picture,
and the transparent picture,
can be used to create a PBR sticker corresponding to the auto-create button.
The material already has a發現 picture.
Open the window of the library,
my library.
Open the first folder of the five materials.
Add the發現 picture.
The strength of the bottom of the發現 picture,
the larger the value,
you can see that the details in the machine are more prominent.
When the value remains the same,
when the value is negative,
visually, the effect of the auto-create will be reversed.
Now drag the find picture to the find picture position.
There is a set of parameters at the bottom,
used to control the three-dimensional effect of the texture surface.
Let's understand the meaning of each parameter corresponding to it.
The degree of change can adjust the maximum height of the surface of the fabric.
If the input value is 3,
the white area will display the maximum height of 3 mm,
and the black area will display the maximum height of 5 mm.
The movement can adjust the distance between the three-dimensional grid and the surface of the fabric.
The height of the decal can be cut off from the grid below the set height.
The particle diameter can adjust the particle diameter of the three-dimensional grid.
The smaller the particle diameter,
the more details can be displayed.
At the same time, the size of the file will also increase.
The rendering time will be longer.
To maintain continuity,
you can open and remove the border line of the adjacent surface.
After understanding the meaning of each parameter,
the degree of change can be entered as 3.
The particle diameter can be entered as 1.
In order to preview and check the effect of its change,
open the render window,
press the render button at the same time.
You can see that the surface of the fabric has three-dimensional details.
After checking, stop rendering
and close the render window.
Drag the transparent picture in the folder into the window.
The mode can be kept as RGB.
Open the surface of the dense texture.
You can see that the fabric in 3D has a hollow effect.
The roughness of the surface,
the right single triangle,
has two options,
intensity and picture.
When the option is intensity,
the larger the value,
the rougher the surface.
Adjusting the reflection intensity
expresses the effect of the material gloss.
The larger the value,
the more gloss the surface has.
Adjusting the metal density
can make the metal effect
applied to the entire plant.
The larger the value,
the stronger the metal effect.
Change the option to picture.
Drag the surface of the rough texture into it.
Reduce the intensity to 65.
Reduce the reflection intensity to 90.
The default black is a completely reflected area.
If the black and white areas are reversed,
you can choose the opposite direction.
Finally, add the metal picture.
The metal density must be adjusted to 100.
The metal effect can be fully displayed.
In the render window,
you can see the final effect
of the glass material.
After the material is completed,
it can be stored locally
so that it can be dragged directly to use next time.
In the property editor,
enter the material,
name, structure, etc. information in the information area.
Click Save.
In CLO,
you can use the physical editor
to design and edit the PBR image separately.
First, open the material of the picture library Connect.
Select Free and Official Accounts.
Find a piece of fabric with a white-blue gradient.
Double-click to add to the object window.
Apply it to the board.
Select this material in the object window.
In the property editor,
click on the three dots next to the material picture.
Open the material editor.
First, let's learn about
the interface layout of the material editor.
At the top,
width and height are used to define the size of the picture.
Click on the triangle on the right of the pixel.
The size unit for setting the picture and the image can be set.
PPI is used to set the resolution of the picture.
Click on this icon.
You can set whether it is transparent or not.
Click on the preview setting button on the right.
In the window, you can choose to display or hide the grid.
The circular opacity can be set to the opacity of the repeated image.
Reset can be restored.
default setting
In the bottom left of the material editor and the layer list,
you can set the layer.
The layer displayed at the moment is the material picture of the fabric.
Click to add.
You can add a new layer.
Click on this icon.
You can select the layer.
You can also duplicate, lock, delete, and select a layer.
If there are multiple layers,
you can drag and drop the layers to adjust the order of their collocation.
Click on the icon on the left of the pixel.
You can display or hide this layer.
The name of the double layer layer can be changed or renamed.
After selecting the layer,
to edit the image properties of the selected layer.
Mixing a blue can mix the selected layer with the bottom layer
in the selected mode.
Colors can be set to the color of the image.
Applying color switching can change the colors of different areas,
using the current pattern of blue and white.
Click on Color Switch.
Enter the number of colors in this pattern, 2.
Purple and blue show two color blocks.
The mouse stops on a color block.
Its corresponding position shows a bright yellow.
Click on the first color block.
The color is set to black.
The second color block is set to red.
Click on Apply.
The new image will cover the original pattern.
Apply to the fabric.
Click on the saved picture in the lower left corner.
The new pattern can be saved in the local file house.
The pattern editor has not been used yet.
The 3D design and production of the spring and summer print ciao
You can comment and click on the comment area.
You can print the print on the surface of the fabric text.
Click on the three dots on the right side of the fabric.
Open the print image, the print image will be added to the bottom of this material.
Select the print in the attribute editor, and enter the print information according to the requirement.
Under the environment settings, you can set the display surface of the print, in the front, reverse or all.
You can also set the repeat type of print as flat, horizontal wrong, vertical wrong, etc.
In addition, you can select a PBR sticker that uses the same PBR as the material.
The PBR stickers of each material can be automatically applied to the print,
and the print and the fabric will be harmoniously integrated to present a more realistic and coordinated visual effect.
You can also use the same picture used and the same material in each sticker,
and selectively apply a specific sticker.
Change the type of print to metal.
Let the print show the metal effect.
The print is the most important part of the print.
The final effect is completed.
Save the entire fabric as a ZFAB file.
You can also save the print attribute.
In addition to the physical appearance of the fabric,
there is also a physical attribute that determines the texture of the fabric,
and the characteristics of its expansion and expansion.
How to get the physical attribute of the fabric in CLO?
First, in the CLO software, there are more than 70 physical attributes of the fabric.
You can directly apply it.
Select the fabric in the object window.
At the bottom of the attribute editor, find the physical attribute.
The physical attribute is displayed on the right side.
Click on the triangle on the right side of the preview.
It shows all the built-in fabric physical attributes of the software.
Click on the physical attribute of this fabric to apply.
Click on the following details.
The physical attribute detail parameters selected for the fabric will be displayed.
Let's understand the core parameters together.
The strength of the fin and the strength of the corner line.
The stretching performance of the fabric.
The larger the fabric, the harder it is stretched.
Such as牛仔布,平纹棉布, etc.
The smaller the fabric, the easier it is stretched.
Such as needle fabric, thin silk, etc.
The hardness of the fabric is controlled by the bending strength.
The larger the number, the harder the fabric.
Like牛仔布 and leather.
The lower the number, the softer the fabric.
Like silk, soft hammer.
In the preview, select the牛仔布.
It is not convenient to observe the wrinkle of the fabric.
Switch to the thick white surface.
Select the Sichuan simulation.
You can see the surface of the fabric in the 3D window.
It is easy to wrinkle and is called hard.
If you choose the needle and thread study,
simulation.
You can see that the surface of the fabric is smooth.
And the feel is stronger.
The transformation of the relevant value is used to indicate the shape of the wrinkle of the fabric.
Now I am demonstrating the V1 fabric of CLO.
When the new user uses the CLO new version,
Only V2 fabric.
In the details of physical properties,
V2 fabric has a higher growth rate than V1 fabric.
Growth rate is used to accurately capture
The non-linear stretching behavior of the actual object.
Increased simulation and scroll accuracy.
In the property editor,
Pull down.
You can see the weight of the fabric.
The friction coefficient and thickness.
In the software, in addition to the fabric.
There is also a physical property preset of the elastic band.
Open the small triangle next to the fabric.
Select the elastic band.
The preset includes the needle elastic band and the shrink elastic band.
You can choose according to your needs.
In addition to the physical properties of the fabric built into the software.
We can also use the CLO fabric measuring device.
Measure the fabric.
Get accurate physical properties.
Like the new fabric measuring device on the right side of the picture.
CLO Z-FAB Kit.
In the two directions of automation and accuracy.
There is a significant improvement.
The CLOF app tool in the software.
Help us quickly and accurately achieve fabric digitization.
Let me give you a brief introduction.
The CLOF app tool in the software.
Come to the software interface.
You can open the CLOF app in three ways.
If you want to create a new fabric from the beginning.
You can click on the object window.
The CLOF app at the top of the fabric.
You will create a new fabric after clicking.
If you want to modify its texture and physical properties on existing fabrics.
You can click on the three small dots on the right side of the fabric.
Select the physical properties or physical properties to start the CLOF app.
You can also click on the single blue fabric of the main dish.
Then click on the CLOF app on the purple menu.
You can start creating new fabrics.
The CLOF app window will pop up in the position of the 2D window.
You can switch with the 2D window.
At the top of the CLOF app window.
You can enter the name of the fabric.
Supplier and all information.
Next is the preview area.
You can click on the link here.
Open the CLOF app related manual for learning.
Below are the physical properties and physical properties.
The basic workflow is to create a physical pattern first.
Then set the physical properties.
When creating a fabric physical pattern under the physical properties.
If you have the CLOF Fab Kit scanning device.
You can click on the first option.
If you do not have the device.
But have scanned image files with other devices.
You can click to open the picture.
In the open file window that appears.
Select the scanned image file.
Then proceed with the physical pattern operation.
If the scanned image file.
Follow the specified file naming rules.
CLOF app can automatically upload.
PBR stickers in the same file.
Click on the physical properties.
You can create a fabric physical property in this interface.
There is a name on the right side.
CLOF Z-FAB fabric scroll test device switch menu.
If you have the CLOF Z-FAB fabric scroll test device.
You can click on use.
If you do not have the device.
You can also choose the type of fabric.
Enter the ingredient percentage.
Weight.
Thickness information.
Quickly and easily create suitable fabric physical properties for clothing.
If you want to learn how to use the CLOF Z-FAB tool specifically.
Create physical and physical properties of digital fabrics.
You can click on the video link in the comment section.
For further study.